# William Bille Meyling

Github: https://github.com/willthbill; LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/linkedin-wbm

I am a 23 year old Computer Science student with a passion for Algorithm Engineering (especially geometry), software design and ML. I have spend the past 8 years finding and pursuing my interests, winning numerous national and international competitions along the way. I see myself as an innovative person, who appreciates simple solutions to complicated problems. My attention to detail, systematic mindset and curiosity makes me good at planning and quickly building large projects, making few mistakes along the way. My native language is Danish.



E-mail: williambillemeyling@gmail.com

#### EDUCATION

University of Copenhagen

Bachelor in Computer Science. Grade: 12

Courses in Algorithms and Cybersecurity

DDD training camps and DDC Cybersecurity courses

**NEXT Sukkertoppen Gymnasium** 

High school. Computer Science and Math. GPA: 11.8

Copenhagen, Denmark Sep. 2020 - Aug. 2023

Denmark

Sep. 2018 - May. 2022 Copenhagen, Denmark

Aug. 2016 - Jun. 2020

EXPERIENCE

### University of Copenhagen

Teaching assistant in the course 'Algorithms and Data structures'

Jobindex

Full-stack Developer. Tools: MySQL, Perl, Vue.js

Copenhagen, Denmark

Feb. 2023 - Mar. 2023

Copenhagen, Denmark

Feb. 2021 - Jan. 2022

Dansk Datalogi Dyst (Danish National Olympiad in Informatics)

Denmark, Indonesia, Germany

Oct. 2020 - present

Volunteer. Designing algorithmic problems used to select students for the national team. Training the national team for the International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI). Preparing courses in advanced (beyond bachelor-level) algorithmic techniques. Deputy leader at IOI 2022. Vice chairman of the technical committee of BOI 2023 (International Competition) (with salary).

Arnvind Group

Frontend Developer. Tools: React. Responsible for a large complex wep-app.

Copenhagen, Denmark Apr. 2019 - Mar. 2020

#### AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

## Winner of Danish National AI Championships 2024

2. place in 2022 and 2023. Competitive ML competition. Deep-learning, ML, algorithms, engineering.

Denmark, Online

Sep. 2022 - Oct. 2024

Winner of Danish National Programming Championships 2023 Denmark, Netherlands and Online Competitive Programming. 4th in 2020, 2nd in 2021, 3rd in 2022, 1st in 2023 (and 3rd in Scandinavia). Qualified for NWERC all four years (Northwestern Europe Regional Contest).

Nov. 2020 - present

Top 12% at NWERC 2023. Winner of Computational Geometry Challenge 2023

Online and in Dallas, Texas

"Unofficial World Championships in Geometric Algorithms" – a research competition called CG:SHOP. Qualified me for SoCG (the most prestigious Computational geometry confer-Media coverage in DR:P1, Ekstra-Bladet, videnskab.dk and more. Statement at https://bit.ly/scienceku-wbm23

Sep. 2022 - Jun. 2023

Winner of Unge Forskere 2020

Copenhagen, Denmark (remote)

Danish National Youth Research Championships 2020. Project about Efficient Graph-based Image-segmentation. Media coverage in DR:P1, DR:P3, Jyllands-posten, videnskab.dk and more. Statement at https://bit.ly/ungefor-wbm20

Apr. 2020

Top 58% at ICPC European Programming Championships 2024

Unge Forskere project received the PRACE Award at EUCYS 2020.

Competitive Programming. Scoreboard: https://bit.ly/euc-wbm24

Mar. 2024

Prague, Czech Republic

'Best Computational Project' at European Science Championships

Salamanca, Spain (remote) Statement at Sep. 2021

https://bit.ly/prace-wbm21 Top 52% at the International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI) 2020

Singapore (remote)

Competitive Programming. IOI participant in 2019 and 2020. Also participated in Baltic Olympiad in Informatics in 2019 and 2020.

Apr. 2019 - Sep. 2020

Winner of Danish National Olympiad in Informatics 2019 and 2020

Dansk Datalogi Dyst. Competitive Programming. Part of the National Team.

Master Title on CodeForces

Competitive Programming. Top 1600 in the world. https://bit.ly/cf-wbm

Next Generation Award 2020 (Skau Reipurth)

Given "as an acknowledgement of his talent, hard work and passion for programming". https://bit.ly/skau-wbm20 Copenhagen, Denmark

Nov. 2020

Sep. 2021 - present

Apr. 2019 - Sep. 2020

Denmark

Online

Copenhagen, Denmark

May. 2022

# Finalist in the Danish Cyber Championships 2022

De Danske Cybermesterskaber 2022. Cybersecurity (CTF) Competition.

### PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

• ExtensionCC: An efficient Convex Cover algorithm developed for CG:SHOP 2023. Publication: https://bit.ly/SoCGpub-wbm23. Bachelor-thesis: https://bit.ly/ba-wbm

- Universal Autonomous Graph-based Image Segmentation with Near-linear Average Complexity: Unge Forskere project. See more at https://bit.ly/eucys-wbm
- Pacup: Open-source tool unifying Linux package managers and making systems reproducible: https://bit.ly/pacup-wbm
- Opener.nvim: Open-source Neovim plugin for workspace / context switching: https://bit.ly/opener-nvim
- Codify: Chrome extension with over 10000 installations.

### SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Theoretical Computer Science: AI, Computational Geometry, Software Design
- Favorite Programming Languages: Rust, C++, Python, JavaScript, C
- Other: Linux, DevOps, Web development, Cybersecurity, Automation, Latex, Video editing

### References

• Mikkel Vind Abrahamsen (Bachelor supervisor)

E-mail: miab@di.ku.dk Mobile: +45 20787534